Caprice Genninger

Software Engineer

Westchester County, NY CapriceLoren@gmail.com

GitHub · LinkedIn · Portfolio

585-713-346

A MERN Stack Developer interested in learning and researching all other languages and frameworks, inspired by the intersection of analytical thought and creativity. A trained researcher and born collaborator, motivated by functionality and scalability. Growth focused and ready to thrive in a challenging environment.

Skills

JavaScript, React.js, Python, Django, Flask, Node.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, JSON, RESTful API, Linux, Mongoose, Express, HTML, CSS, GitHub

Projects

Social Media Full Stack Website

- Collaborated with a team of 10 engineers to create a social media site.
- Created backend with Python, Django and PostgreSQL, designed front end using React.js.

PetLyfe ECommerce Full Stack Website

- Collaborated with a team of 5 engineers to create a mock ECommerce website for pet goods.
- Created backend with MongoDB, Mongoose and Express, designed front end using React.js.

Experience

Software Engineering Fellow • General Assembly

September 2022 - December 2022 • New York, New York

- 14 Week, full time Software Engineering immersive program.
- Developed applications using MERN stack as well as Python, Django, PostgreSQL.
- RESTful API deployment with full CRUD functionality.

Laboratory Technician • North West Wine

June 2021 - January 2022 • Portland, Oregon

- Managed lab analysis and status updates for over 2,000 barrels of wine through database management.
- Authored Standard Operating Procedures and data heavy spreadsheets for the department.
- Reduced wait times for status updates by 50%, allowing wine makers ample time to decide on additions or alterations.
- Implemented and maintained laboratory organization by categorizing over 300 pieces of inventory.

Research Assistant • Horton Laboratories

August 2019 - March 2020 • Syracuse, NY

- Systematized laboratory organization by developing both physical and digital management strategies for over 200 samples.
- Created digital records for experimental data by utilizing database management.

Research Assistant • Green Laboratories

January 2018 - December 2018 • Syracuse, NY

- Conducted water analysis for the city of Salt Lake, Utah using qPCR.
- Created data curves and interpreted statistical analysis for over 20 samples per week.
- Homogenized tissue samples and eluted DNA, using qBit to quantify DNA composition of samples.
- Managed project and worked with little supervision, requiring outstanding independent time management.

Education

Certificate of Completion • Software Engineering Immersive • General Assembly • New York, NY **Bachelor Of Science** • SUNY College Of Environmental Science And Forestry • Syracuse, NY